Arthur Guimaraes Serafim

Software Engineer | Guarapari, Espirito Santo <u>arthurserafim.com</u> | arthur@dev.net.br <u>LinkedIn Profile | GitHub Profile</u>

CAREER SUMMARY

Experienced Front End Developer and Software Engineer with a detailed history of collaborating with stakeholders and driving exceptional results. Currently envisions blending a unique combination of experience, skillset, and motivation to land an exciting and challenging position for a reputable firm in the coming weeks in order to jointly ensure the utmost in quality and user experience.

STRENGTHS & SKILLS

HTML 5, CSS3, SCSS | JavaScript, React, Redux | Vue, Angular, Svelte | Node, Express, MongoDB | Coding & Troubleshooting | Technical Documentation | User Experience | Route Planning | Software Optimization

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | GreenMile | US & Brazil Base (Online/Remote) | 2020 – present

- Implemented data plotting platforms while running performance analysis for a routing software that is being tested and evaluated by Solar, a Latin American company responsible for Coca-Cola fulfillment, as well as Linde and others.
- Collaborated with multiple clients and departments, while communicating status and proposals.
- Analyzed data and effectively coordinated the installation or modification of new or existing systems.
- Managed the software development lifecycle and monitored the system performance and communicated key project data to team members, while building strong cohesion among the team.
- Championed innovative solutions that proactively met the technical needs of our company.
- Implemented end-to-end testing, while steadfastly shaping the future of our systems.
- Planned and executed well-designed, testable code and ensured software was always up to date.
- Produced specs, determined feasibility, and developed flowcharts, layouts, and documentation and designed and developed a platform utilizing a range of configuration management technologies.

React Developer | XFive.co | US Base (Online/Remote) | 2019 – present

- Involved in all phases of web page development, including analysis, structure, design, development, testing, and documentation, while proactively championing the end user experience.
- Balanced functional and aesthetic design, ensuring web design was optimized for mobile.
- Built reusable code for future use and optimized the web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Leveraged a variety of markup languages to write web pages, steadfastly maintaining brand consistency throughout the design and project lifecycle.
- Collaborated with a team of architects and back-end developers, gathering requirements and enhancing the application's functionality and overall design and features.
- Worked within a team involved in developing the UI, layout, and front-end programming for the web applications, utilizing HTML, CSS, React and JavaScript, while matching the requirements of sprint.
- Utilized directives and modules, creating reusable components incorporated across whole projects.

• Leveraged extensive knowledge of programming, including HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, and Redux for project design.

Web Developer | Goodie Website | US & Europe Base (Online/Remote) | 2019 – present

- Involved in all phases of web site and app development, including design and maintenance.
- Conferred with teams to resolve conflicts and prioritize needs, while developing content criteria, and/or choosing an appropriate solution.
- Directed or performed website updates and developed or validated test routines and schedules to ensure that test cases mimicked external interfaces, while addressing all browser and device types.
- Determined user needs by analyzing technical requirements and edited, wrote, or designed website content, and directed team members to produce content.
- Maintained an understanding of the latest web applications and programming practices through education, study, and participation in various conferences, workshops, and groups.
- Backed up files to local directories for recovery and identified problems uncovered by customer feedback and tested and corrected or referred problems to appropriate personnel for correction.
- Evaluated code and proactively ensured it always met my own rigorous standards, while being valid, properly structured, and compatible with browsers, devices, or operating systems.

Front End Developer | Yooga Tecnologia | Vitória, Espírito Santo, Brazil | 2020

- Maintained and improved the website and enhanced the application for maximum speed and scalability for this SAAS companies that sells ERP solutions.
- Focused primarily on delivery application and developing the complete front end of the MVP for a table management system.
- Created user-friendly pages and designed mobile-based features, including Vouchers and Drive in Withdraw, which have been used thousands of times already.
- Collaborated with back-end developers and web designers and improved usability.
- Received feedback from users and built solutions and wrote functional requirement guides.
- Validated input before submitting to back end and helped back-end (developers) with coding and troubleshooting, while creating quality mockups and prototypes aligned with brand consistency.
- Bridged the gap between graphic design and technical implementation and remained up-to-date on emerging technologies, while defining how the application should look and operate.
- Collaborated with internal stakeholders and developed the UI, layout, and front-end programming for web applications using HTML, CSS, Angular, React, Vue, TypeScript and JavaScript.

SPECIFIC PROJECTS

Web Developer | Mouse One Gaming | Washington, D.C. (Online/Remote) | 2020

- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces using knowledge of HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, WordPress API, and Shopify for this gaming technology company.
- Developed the next generation integration platform for internal applications, maintained existing applications, and designed and delivered new ones.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Category) | Computer Engineering | University of Vila Velha | Espirito Santo,
Brazil